<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="http://kellenfujimoto.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <title> on Kellen Fujimoto </title>
        <generator>Hugo</generator>

        <link>http://kellenfujimoto.com/index.xml</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>kellenfujimoto.com by Kellen Fujimoto is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 20:40:04 PST</pubDate>
        <description>I am a social justice, movement, and tech blogger in Seattle. Warning: site contains strong opinions on politics, and treating other human beings with decency. Opinions expressed are author&#39;s own.</description>
        
        <item>
            <title>About Me</title>
            <link>http://kellenfujimoto.com/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 20:40:04 PST</pubDate>
            <author>contact@kellenfujimoto.com</author>
            <guid>http://kellenfujimoto.com/about/</guid>
            <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a (practically) native Seattleite of a decidedly nerdy persuasion; the fact that I have a blog would be a good indication of that, I guess. When I&amp;rsquo;m not typing things into here, I&amp;rsquo;m probably out &lt;a href=&#34;http://parkourvisions.org&#34;&gt;jumping on stuff&lt;/a&gt;, making &lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/fujimotophotography&#34;&gt;pretty photos&lt;/a&gt;, and tinkering with various software projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in a cute little SLU apartment with my partner No&amp;euml;l and our cat Bella. We&amp;rsquo;re both homebodys at heart, but we do find time to explore the area (she&amp;rsquo;s from the east coast) and sample the excellent culinary options available to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/img/about-family.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Our growing family&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;And this site?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love building websites. This site is built on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.com&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;. Most posts for the time being will be on my various adventures in code slinging, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to update this regularly with links I find interesting. &lt;a href=&#34;http://kellenfujimoto.com/rss.xml&#34;&gt;Subscribe to the RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/rakenodiax&#34;&gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see when I post, and thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>

