<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="http://kellenfujimoto.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <title>Kellen Fujimoto </title>
        <generator>Hugo</generator>

        <link>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/index.xml</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>kellenfujimoto.com by Kellen Fujimoto is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 18:27:14 PST</pubDate>
        <description>I am a social justice, movement, and tech blogger in Seattle. Warning: site contains strong opinions on politics, and treating other human beings with decency. Opinions expressed are author&#39;s own.</description>
        
        <item>
            <title>Automated Hugo posting with Dropbox</title>
            <link>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/2014/11/automated-hugo-posting-with-dropbox/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 18:27:14 PST</pubDate>
            <author>contact@kellenfujimoto.com</author>
            <guid>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/2014/11/automated-hugo-posting-with-dropbox/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown together a little script to automatically build my Hugo site when I write a new draft (using Drafts 4 on my phone — that&amp;rsquo;s the subject of another post, though). It&amp;rsquo;s hacked-together Perl and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alandipert/fswatch&#34;&gt;file system monitor&lt;/a&gt; right now; I&amp;rsquo;m planning on cleaning it up and putting it on github when I get my act together, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>the architect got left behind</title>
            <link>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/2014/11/the-architect-got-left-behind/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 23:02:04 PST</pubDate>
            <author>contact@kellenfujimoto.com</author>
            <guid>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/2014/11/the-architect-got-left-behind/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Way back when I was in high school, all of my schoolwork fell into a similar pattern: I would be either monumentally enthusiastic or apprehensive towards every assignment. I&amp;rsquo;d dive head first into a project, or freeze at the sight of 80 whole pages of reading a night.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1-the-architect-got-left-behind&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1-the-architect-got-left-behind&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to attend a school that &lt;a href=&#34;http://pscs.org/about-pscs/&#34;&gt;encourages personal growth and self reflection&lt;/a&gt;, and so I learned to structure my work and channel my enthusiasm into productivity. It is a continuing process, but I like to think that I correct myself earlier as I practice more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This diversion is an explanation. Though I am extremely excited to get Tsunami off the ground, I jumped into prototyping without considering the structure of the app. In plowing forward along the critical path, I boxed myself into a monolithic app which would make future improvements difficult at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping this in mind, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be blogging more about the &lt;em&gt;structure&lt;/em&gt; of Tsunami, and developing a set of meta-goals for the project to guide future development. Expect more soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&#34;fn1-the-architect-got-left-behind&#34;&gt;I know, just so much, right?&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1-the-architect-got-left-behind&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>tsunami notes 1: format choices</title>
            <link>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/2014/10/tsunami-notes-1-format-choices/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 23:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
            <author>contact@kellenfujimoto.com</author>
            <guid>http://kellenfujimoto.com/tech/2014/10/tsunami-notes-1-format-choices/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes, it&amp;#39;s best to just start *somewhere*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project has been percolating on my back burner for a long while. My friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ericjusino&#34;&gt;Eric&lt;/a&gt; came to me with an idea for a truly decentralized social network: a protocol similar to email in spirit but more akin to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent&#34;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt; in implementation. Obviously, discoverability is a challenge in any social network, and one without a central directory harder still. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, and it has to be both secure and anonymous while in plain sight. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is obviously a massive project to bite off, and I want to eventually release this protocol into the open source world and see what direction it takes (it&amp;#39;s only appropriate that such a cooperative network should be built *by* the community). I&amp;#39;m going to be using this blog as a journal of my progress and as a way to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubber_duck_debugging&#34;&gt;think out loud&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; about making this. There&amp;#39;ll be occasional opinion posts on here, but I want to focus on the project. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the scope of this, I&amp;#39;m just going to start building the basic structure I&amp;#39;m looking for so I can begin iterating on the protocol as soon as possible. As this project needs a name (and our joke one of &amp;ldquo;GitFace&amp;rdquo; seems a bit rough), I&amp;#39;m going to go ahead and name it Tsunami. It&amp;#39;s a Japanese word (yay, heritage!), and is reminiscent of how messages propagate through the network, making minimal waves before reaching their destination. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I was hammering-out a basic format for Tsunami messages. To test the network implementation (which I will probably the next post) as soon as possible, I&amp;#39;m just doing a basic JSON structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;{
    &amp;quot;kind&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;tsunami:alpha&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;sha512 hex digest&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;payload&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;metadata&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;my first title&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;verification&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;should decrypt to same as message id&amp;quot;
        },
        &amp;quot;body&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;payload encrypted using public key encryption. Public key is functionally the to: field&amp;quot;
    }
}&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My good friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/russellhay&#34;&gt;Russell&lt;/a&gt; suggested a binary format to save space and prevent the need to parse out many messages; streamlining this process will result in a huge amount of saved time given how frequently these messages are going to be whizzing to and fro. I&amp;#39;m designing the server so that different message formats can be interchanged without affecting the remaining code. The current version is part of the document string, so changing implementations (such as modifying the encryption or hashing algorithms) can be propagated and declared properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want this format to be relatively generic — not just a messaging platform, but for syndication, mailing lists, etc. &lt;strong&gt;Keeping the protocol flexible is a primary concern.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to get in touch about this project? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/rakenodiax&#34;&gt;Find me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>

